GARICK MENDEZ

+1 (512) 947-9149 Spmendez1@stedwards.edu Spmendez1@st

Summary

Passionate and **detail-oriented** Software Engineer with strong skills and proven experience in modern technologies, including React.js, TypeScript, Python, and a wide range of programming languages and frameworks. I create engaging and responsive user interfaces by thinking outside the box to solve problems. Bilingual -- Spanish and English

EDUCATION

St. Edward's University | Austin, TX 2020-2024

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Minor in Business

SKILLS

- Languages/Frameworks: React.js,
 TypeScrypt, Tailwind CSS, HTML5, CSS3,
 Next.js, Remix, Python, SQL, GraphQL, PHP,
 Swift, Node.is.
- **Development Tools:** npm, Git, Trello, Figma, Docker, Bitbucket.
- Languages: Spanish (native), English (mastery).

PROJECTS

Basketball Analytics Platform (Hooplogic)

- Engineered and developed the front-end for a responsive, user-centered service catering to prop bettors, implementing graphical data with API and D3.js.
- Accelerated access to graphical data by creating multi-page web app using React and CSS which resulted in a 40% improvement.

• Employee Management Service (Worklink)

- Engineered web application for managers and employees to create, delegate, and complete tasks.
- Designed and implemented multiple pages using React, HTML, CSS, and JSON which included supply and demand sides.

Autonomous Vehicle Delivery Service (WeGo)

- Developed a supply and demand service for a Transportation-as-a-Service platform using APIs, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS to create user-centered web application.
- Excelled in software engineering and design using Figma, Trello, and Selenium in an agile scrum environment where CI/CD was key.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Development Intern | Austin, TX

Cooledtured | Nov 2023 - March 2023

- Leveraged expertise in React.js, GraphQL, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS to create dynamic, responsive components and pages for Shopify Hydrogen e-commerce, elevating UX.
- Collaborated closely with experienced developers to maintain the app and shape the **UI/UX** design of the platform.
- Ensured version control and streamlined collaboration using **Git** and **npm**.

Lead Guest Relations Agent | Austin, TX

St. Edward's University | May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Optimized team workflow by scheduling and coordinating a team of 4 GRAs, enhancing workflow efficiency.
- Managed projects and collaborated with the Assist. Director of Events and Conferences to seamlessly arrange for client arrivals.

Full-stack Intern | Austin, TX

Renzoe Box | Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Developed reliable and stable web environment, showcasing proficiency in **Python Flask** and **SQL** for back-end development.
- Implemented responsive, user-friendly pages using HTML5, React, and CSS in collaboration with seasoned developers encouraging Agile Scrum practices and a fast-paced work environment.
- Incorporated **Docker** to streamline deployment and enhance scalability, ensuring a seamless hosting environment.

SAP Intern I & II | Santiago de Chile

ERP Chile Consulting | June 2021 - July 2022

- SAP S/4HANA: Excelled SAP payroll processes, designed org. structures, functions, and positions for an international company.
- Leveraged my skills in ABAP to develop queries to ensure accurate and timely access to data.
- Created and managed personnel data, handling various infotypes for international enterprise systems.